记住，不变量是
Now, remember that invariant is a property that's
整个程序都是这样。
true for the entire program.
在物体不变的情况下
Which in the case of an invariant about an object
表示对象的整个生命周期。
means the entire lifetime of the object.
为了证明不变性，我们需要
To show that invariant holds, we need
使不变量在对象的初始状态下为真
to make the invariant true in the initial state of the object
当它第一次创建并确保
when it's first created and ensure
所有对对象的更改都保持不变。
that all changes to the object keep the invariant true.
所以在ATP操作的种类上，
So in terms of kinds of ATP operations,
这是什么意思？
what does this mean?
这意味着创作者和制作人
This means that creators and producers, which
是创造物体初始状态的东西，
are the things that create the initial state of the object,
必须为新对象实例建立不变量。
must establish the invariant for new object instances.
变异者和观察者
And mutator and observers, which are
在对象的生命周期内调用，
called over the lifetime of the object,
必须保持不变。
must preserve the invariant.
现在，销售代表暴露的风险使这种情况更加严重
Now, the risk of rep exposure makes this situation much more
很复杂。
complicated.
所以代表被曝光了。
So the rep is exposed.
对象可能会在程序中的任何地方更改，
And the object might be changed anywhere in the program,
不仅仅是在ADT的行动中。
not just in the ADT's operations.
我们不能保证不变量仍然有效
And we can't guarantee that the invariants still holds
在那些武断的改变之后。
after those arbitrary changes.
所以证明不变性的全部规则
So the full rule for proving invariance
这叫做结构归纳法--
is-- and this is called structural induction--
如果不变量或抽象数据类型
if an invariant or an abstract data type
是由创作者和制作人建立的
is established by its creators and producers
被叛变者和观察者保存
and preserved by its mutilators and observers
也不会暴露于表象，然后
and no representation exposure occurs, then
不变量适用于抽象数据的所有实例
the invariant is true of all instances of the abstract data
键入。
type.